# Ruan Pingcheng (PhD)

Gender: Male Nationality: China (Singapore PR)

Mobile Number: (+65) 9807 3466

Email Address: ruanpingcheng@gmail.com

Google Scholar: <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=Nm-24AUAAAAJ">https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=Nm-24AUAAAAJ</a>

Personal Website: <a href="https://ruan0007.github.io">https://ruan0007.github.io</a>

Mailing Address:

Viva Vista, #03-21,

3 South Buona Vista Road, Singapore, 118136

# **Personal Statement**

I am currently working as a Backend Engineer (Infrastructure) in ByteDance, Singapore. My previous research focuses on blockchains, and my interest spans from distributed systems, databases to all other large-scale data processing platforms. During my PhD study, I am the award winner of VLDB 2019 Best Paper Award and SIGMOD 2020 Research Highlight Award. During my Bachelor study, I am the only student in my cohort who is in the Dean's List (top 5%) throughout academic years.

# **Education**

# National University of Singapore (NUS), Singapore

Aug 2016~Mar 2022

Doctor of Philosophy (Computer Science)

- Supervised by Distinguished Prof OOI Beng Chin in School of Computing
- Thesis: Blockchains: Novel Data Systems and Beyond

# Nanyang Technological University (NTU), Singapore

Aug 2012~Aug 2016

Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science)

- Graduated with First Class Honors from School of Computer Science and Engineering (SCSE)
- Specialized in High Performance Computing, Information System
- Obtained Grade Point Average: 4.86/5.00 (3<sup>rd</sup> in the cohort)

SM2 Bridging Program

July 2011~Aug 2012

 Undertook a one-year pre-college program with English and Science courses, exclusively for SM2 scholars

## Nanjing Foreign Language School, Jiangsu, China

Sept 2006~Jun 2011

Middle School and High School

• Maintained top 5 percent on academic performance

#### Career

# ByteDance, Singapore

Software Engineer (Infrastructure)

Mar 2022~Present

• Building the next-generation, industry-scale, highly available data systems

#### School of Computing (SoC), National University of Singapore

Research Fellow Research Assistant Sept 2021~Mar 2022

Aug 2016~Sept 2021

- Supervised by Distinguished Prof OOI Beng Chin
- Involved all blockchain-related systems in our team, including:
  - **BlockBench**: the first benchmarking framework for private blockchain systems. It serves as a fair means of comparison for different platforms



- and enables deeper understanding of different system design choices.
- ForkBase: an efficient storage engine dedicated for blockchain and collaborative analysis systems. It is featured for its forking semantics, chunk-level deduplication and tamper-evidence.
- FabricSharp: a variant of Hyperledger Fabric 2.2, a permissioned blockchain platform from Hyperledger. Compared with the vanilla version, FabricSharp is renowned for fine-grained secure data provenance, state-of-the-art transaction management, and a blockchain native storage engine, ForkBase.

## **Publications**

- P. Ruan, Y.Kanza, B. C. Ooi, D. Srivastava, LedgerView: Access-Control Views on Hyperledger Fabric. ACM SIGMOD 2022
- Z. Ge, D. Loghin, B. C. Ooi, **P. Ruan**, T. Wang: *Hybrid Blockchain Database Systems: Design and Performance*. **VLDB 2022**
- P. Ruan, A. Dinh, D. Loghin, M. Zhang, G. Chen, Q. Lin, B. C. Ooi: *Blockchains and Distributed Databases: Dichotomy and Fusion*. ACM SIGMOD 20211
- P. Ruan, D. Loghin, Q.-T. ta, M Zhang, G. Chen, B. C. Ooi: A Transactional Perspective on Execute-Order-Validate Blockchains. ACM SIGMOD 2020
- P. Ruan, A. Dinh, Q. Lin, M. Zhang, G. Chen, B. C. Ooi: Revealing Every Story of Data in Blockchain Systems. ACM SIGMOD 2020 RESEARCH HIGHLIGHT AWARD
- Q. Lin, K. Yang, A. Dinh, Q. Cai, G. Chen, B. C. Ooi, P. Ruan, S. Wang, Z. Xie, M. Zhang,
   O. Vandans: ForkBase: Immutable, Tamper-evident Storage Substrate for Branchable
   Applications. IEEE ICDE 2020 Demo
- P. Ruan, G. Chen, A. Dinh, Q. Lin, B.C. Ooi, M. Zhang: FineGrained, Secure and Efficient
  Data Provenance on Blockchain Systems. VLDB 2019 BEST PAPER (the
  extended version published in The VLDB Journal 2021)
- S. Wang, T. T. A. Dinh, Q. Lin, Z. Xie, M. Zhang, Q. Cai, G. Chen, B.C. Ooi, P. Ruan: ForkBase: An Efficient Storage Engine for Blockchain and Forkable Applications. VLDB 2018
- A. Dinh, J. Wang, S. Wang, G. Chen, W.-N. Chin, Q. Lin, B. C. Ooi, **P. Ruan**, K.-L. Tan, Z. Xie, H. Zhang, and M. Zhang: *UStore: a distributed storage with rich semantics*.
- P. Ruan, G. Chen, A. Dinh, Q. Lin, D. Loghin, B. C. Ooi, M. Zhang: *Blockchains and Distributed Databases: A Twin Study*

# Awards

- Honorable Mention for ACM SIGMOD Jim Gray Dissertation Award, 2022
- ACM SIGMOD Research Highlight Award, 2020
- Dean's Graduate Research Excellence Award, SoC NUS, 2020
- VLDB Best Paper Award, 2019
- Graduate Research Excellence Award, SoC NUS, 2019
- Hewlett-Packard Gold Medal, SCSE NTU, 2016
- Dean's List, SCSE NTU, 2016
- Dean's List, SCSE NTU, 2015
- Dean's List, SCSE NTU, 2014
- Dean's List, SCSE NTU, 2013
- 15th SM2 Scholarship, Ministry of Education, Singapore, 2012